<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[the smallest pixel.]]></title>
  <link href="smallestpixel.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="smallestpixel.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-08T15:27:45-06:00</updated>
  <id>smallestpixel.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cameron Banga]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[cameron@cameronbanga.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Times, They Aren't A Changin']]></title>
    <link href="smallestpixel.org/blog/2013/01/08/the-times-they-arent-a-changin/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-08T14:56:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>smallestpixel.org/blog/2013/01/08/the-times-they-arent-a-changin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fun little OS X easter egg that I&#8217;ve never noticed before. I&#8217;m a huge Apple and Macintosh history buff, so if I didn&#8217;t know this, you probably didn&#8217;t either.</p>

<p>In Mountain Lion (and assumably earlier versions of OS X too, but I don&#8217;t have any past versions on hand to try with), when a file download fails to complete or is cancelled before the entire file is transferred, an arbitrary timestamp is given to the file&#8217;s &#8220;Date Modified&#8221; attribute.</p>

<p><img src="http://images.smallestpixel.org.s3.amazonaws.com/Screen%20Shot%202013-01-08%20at%202.43.12%20PM.png" title="January 24th, 1984" alt="January 24th, 1984" /></p>

<p>This timestamp, as shown above, is midnight PST on January 24th, 1984. Why&#8217;s this date important in Apple history? Back on this Tuesday afternoon, Steve Jobs unveiled the original Macintosh to the world at an Apple Stockholder meeting in one of his first Stevenotes. Here&#8217;s a fun video of the announcement, if you&#8217;ve never seen it.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4KkENSYkMgs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Another fun Apple history fact. In the video above, the Macintosh introduces itself using a synthetic voice while also playing a variety of impressive (at the time) screen animations. This demo was actually performed on a 512k Macintosh that wouldn&#8217;t be released for another nine months, as the original Macintosh didn&#8217;t have enough memory to power the presentation. <a href="http://folklore.org/StoryView.py?project=Macintosh&amp;story=Intro_Demo.txt&amp;topic=Marketing">According to Andy Hertzfeld</a>, it was one of only two Mac 512k prototypes in existence at that time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing your humble narrator.]]></title>
    <link href="smallestpixel.org/blog/2013/01/06/introducing-your-humble-narrator/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-06T21:15:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>smallestpixel.org/blog/2013/01/06/introducing-your-humble-narrator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sigh, the first paragraph. I&#8217;ve started a handful of blogs, yet none have had a memorable start from what I can remember, so I&#8217;m going to ideally make this post short and sweet. Think of this as the first snowball that will hopefully roll down the hill and become an avalanche.</p>

<p>While I think my background is rather unimportant, I do think it will be relevant when trying to understand the point of view behind this blog. Through better understanding me, I hope that you will also be able to better understand my posts.</p>

<p>My name is Cameron Banga, and I am currently search lead designer at <a href="http://9magnets.com">9magnets, LLC</a>. I co-founded the company after graduating college in 2010, and we&#8217;ve worked on nearly 100 iPhone, iPad, and Android apps since opening our doors.</p>

<p>Along the way, I&#8217;ve also written a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/iPhone-Interface-Cookbook-Cameron-Banga/dp/1849691142">book</a> on iOS user interface design and have given a variety of talks on mobile tech and the future of entrepreneurship. When it comes to my personal interests, I really enjoy taking photos with my Canon Rebel T2i, vinyl albums, and soccer.</p>

<p>For this blog, my goal is to lend my opinion on starting a self-sustainable tech company, productivity, improving workflows, design, online data security and anything else that I think I can offer valuable input on. My only goal with each post will be to write something that will help you learn or make you think.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t have a tangible idea as to how often I&#8217;ll post or how long the blog will last. It&#8217;s more of a personal experiment for myself that I&#8217;ll be more than happy to share. I suppose I&#8217;ll write for as long as it feels right, and that&#8217;s about all I can promise.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading along until the end, I hope you enjoy what you read. If you have any questions, comments or suggestions, feel free to reach out whenever via <a href="mailto:cameron@cameronbanga.com">email</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
